export const questions = [
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following DOES NOT one of the reasons behind the Military Coup of 1980 in Turkey?",
    correctAnswer: "Effective party politics",
    propositions: [
      "Unsolved economic crisis",
      "Sectarian and ethnic conflicts",
      "Effective party politics",
      "Rise of political violence",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following DOES NOT match?",
    correctAnswer: "National Salvation Party - Bülent Ecevit",
    propositions: [
      "Democratic Party - Adnan Menderes",
      "National Salvation Party - Bülent Ecevit",
      "Republican People's Party - İsmet İnönü",
      "Justice Party - Süleyman Demirel",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following WAS NOT one of the results of the First Gulf War?",
    correctAnswer: "Turkish economy benefited from the War.",
    propositions: [
      "Turkish economy benefited from the War.",
      "Northern Iraq practically evolved into a separate political entity after the War.",
      "Turkish government prevented crossings in the Iraq-Turkey border.",
      "The UN created a security zone in Northern Iraq.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which one of the politicians below was involved in the National Outlook movement during his political career?",
    correctAnswer: "Necmettin Erbakan",
    propositions: [
      "Necmettin Erbakan",
      "Deniz Baykal",
      "Bulent Ecevit",
      "İsmet İnönü",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following WAS NOT one of the most pressing questions of the 1990s?",
    correctAnswer:
      "Turkey's political influence on the Central Asian governments",
    propositions: [
      "Turkey's political influence on the Central Asian governments",
      "Economic crises",
      "Membership to the EU",
      "Kurdish Question",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following CANNOT BE one of the examples of political violence in the 1970s?",
    correctAnswer: "The abolishment of martial law in big cities",
    propositions: [
      "Maraş Çorum Massacres",
      "The Taksim Incident of 1 May 1977",
      "The abolishment of martial law in big cities",
      "Shared neighborhoods between rightist and leftist groups",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Democratic Party government was removed from power by a military coup that took place on 12 March 1971.",
    correctAnswer: "False",
    propositions: ["True", "False"],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following WAS NOT one of the important features of the elections of 1950?",
    correctAnswer:
      "Reformism from top-down was commonly accepted by the people.",
    propositions: [
      "Paternalism and control from the center were rejected.",
      '"Going to the people" became one of the most popular political motto.',
      "Reformism from top-down was commonly accepted by the people.",
      "It was about going against a statist tradition.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which one of the developments below DID NOT take place in the course of the year 1999?",
    correctAnswer: "Erbakan-Ciller coalition",
    propositions: [
      "The government signed a new stand-by agreement with the IMF",
      "Erbakan-Ciller coalition",
      "Turkey's candidacy for the European Union was reaffirmed in the Helsinki Summit",
      "Thousands of citizens lost their lives in the earthquake that occurred around the Gulf of İzmit",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Turkish economy became largely liberalized and numerous trade and import barriers were removed during the 1980s.",
    correctAnswer: "True",
    propositions: ["True", "False"],
  },
  {
    question:
      "12 March 1971 memorandum (muhtira) expressed an open distrust of politics and politicians by handing over the power to:",
    correctAnswer: "Army officers",
    propositions: [
      "Army officers",
      "Judges",
      "Workers and Peasants",
      "Technocrats",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the below is a more proper definition of the Cold War?",
    correctAnswer:
      "Political military and ideological competition between the Soviet Union and the United States after the Second World War",
    propositions: [
      "Political military and ideological competition between the Soviet Union and the United States after the Second World War",
      "Diplomatic complications between European powers that finally led to the First World War",
      "Political disagreements between Turkey and Greece over the Cyprus Question",
      "Economic competition between France and Britain after the Second World War",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "The principal goal of the decisions announced by the National Security Council on 28 February 1997 (28 Subat Kararlar) was to restructure and reform the Turkish economy and finance.",
    correctAnswer: "False",
    propositions: ["True", "False"],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Proclaimed in August 1960, the Republic of Cyprus' Independence, territorial integrity, and constitutional order were guaranteed by Greece, Great Britain, and Turkey.",
    correctAnswer: "True",
    propositions: ["True", "False"],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following DOES NOT represent economics in Turkey in the 1960s and 1970s?",
    correctAnswer: "Decrease of black markets",
    propositions: [
      "Rising inflation",
      "Decrease of black markets",
      "Constant trade deficit",
      "Increasing energy prices",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which one of the following WAS NOT the main reason behind the growth of political radicalism in the 1960s in Turkey?",
    correctAnswer:
      "On March 12, 1971, the Chief of General Staff demanded that a strong and credible government be formed and carry out reforms in a Kemalist spirit.",
    propositions: [
      "The publication of political periodicals and political debating societies affected the society.",
      "There was a growing student population and industrial proletariat.",
      "People became more mobile both socially and physically in this period.",
      "On March 12, 1971, the Chief of General Staff demanded that a strong and credible government be formed and carry out reforms in a Kemalist spirit.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following WAS NOT one of the important features of the elections of 1950?",
    correctAnswer:
      "Reformism from top-down was commonly accepted by the people.",
    propositions: [
      "It was about going against a statist tradition.",
      "Paternalism and control from the center were rejected.",
      "Reformism from top-down was commonly accepted by the people.",
      '"Going to the people" became one of the most popular political motto.',
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following DOES NOT one of the reasons behind the Military Coup of 1980 in Turkey?",
    correctAnswer: "Effective party politics",
    propositions: [
      "Rise of political violence",
      "Unsolved economic crisis",
      "Effective party politics",
      "Sectarian and ethnic conflicts",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Compared to the Constitution of 1961, the Constitution of 1982 diminished the political authority of the National Security Council.",
    correctAnswer: "False",
    propositions: ["True", "False"],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the below was NOT one of the reasons underlying the economic boom of the 1950-1954 period?",
    correctAnswer: "Planned economy and industrialization",
    propositions: [
      "Credits and loans provided by the USA and international financial institutes with low interest rates",
      "Increasing use of imported machinery in agricultural production",
      "Planned economy and industrialization",
      "Rise of agricultural productivity",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "After the Military Coup of May 27, 1960, Cemal Gürsel became the new President of Turkey.",
    correctAnswer: "True",
    propositions: ["True", "False"],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which party dominated Turkish politics by scoring consecutive electoral successes until 1989 and by maintaining the majority government in 1981?",
    correctAnswer: "Motherland Party",
    propositions: [
      "Republican People's Party",
      "Social Democrat Populist Party",
      "True Path Party",
      "Motherland Party",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which city served as the provisional capital during the Turkish War of Independence?",
    correctAnswer: "Ankara",
    propositions: ["Bursa", "Ankara", "Izmir", "Istanbul"],
  },
  {
    question:
      "During the İsmet İnönü era, which foreign policy principle guided Turkey's stance in international affairs?",
    correctAnswer: "Neutrality",
    propositions: [
      "Isolationism",
      "Interventionism",
      "Neutrality",
      "Expansionism",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "What were the main causes and outcomes of the Balkan Wars (1912-1913) and how did these events impact the geopolitical situation in the region?",
    correctAnswer: "Shifting alliances and territorial changes",
    propositions: [
      "Shifting alliances and territorial changes",
      "Economic cooperation and cultural exchanges",
      "Religious reforms and social revolutions",
      "Military isolation and international sanctions",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "What was the outcome of the Treaty of Sèvres (1920) for the Ottoman Empire?",
    correctAnswer: "Territorial losses and occupation",
    propositions: [
      "Territorial losses and occupation",
      "Economic prosperity",
      "Alliance with the Allied Powers",
      "Full sovereignty and independence",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "What was the main objective of the Turkish National Movement during the War of Independence?",
    correctAnswer: "Preservation of territorial integrity and independence",
    propositions: [
      "Expansion of the caliphate",
      "Preservation of territorial integrity and independence",
      "Restoration of the Ottoman Empire",
      "Establishment of a communist state",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is correct for Turkey’s involvement in the Second World War?",
    correctAnswer:
      "Turkey was sympathetic to Britain and its Allies but declared war against Germany only symbolically at the end of the war",
    propositions: [
      "Turkey actively fought on the same side with Germany",
      "From the start to the end Turkey never declared war on Germany",
      "Turkey was sympathetic to Britain and its Allies but declared war against Germany only symbolically at the end of the war",
      "Turkey actively fought on the same side with Britain",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "During the early Republic which group of people were targeted by the Population Exchange between Greece and Turkey?",
    correctAnswer: "Greeks",
    propositions: ["Kurds", "Greeks", "Circassians", "Armenians"],
  },
  {
    question:
      "What was the political ideology of the Republican People’s Party during the One-Party State period?",
    correctAnswer: "Kemalism",
    propositions: ["Monarchy", "Fascism", "Kemalism", "Communism"],
  },
  {
    question:
      "In 1928, what significant change was made to the Turkish alphabet as part of the language reform?",
    correctAnswer: "Adoption of the Latin alphabet",
    propositions: [
      "Introduction of Cyrillic script",
      "Incorporation of Greek letters",
      "Adoption of the Latin alphabet",
      "Implementation of Arabic script",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "What event marked the end of the Ottoman Empire and the beginning of the Republic of Turkey?",
    correctAnswer: "Treaty of Lausanne",
    propositions: [
      "Treaty of Versailles",
      "Treaty of Sèvres",
      "Treaty of London",
      "Treaty of Lausanne",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which one of the following was NOT the main aim of the Marshall Plan?",
    correctAnswer: "to establish an international cultural pact",
    propositions: [
      "to help the Europeans in terms of strengthening their economy",
      "to sustain lucrative export markets for US industry",
      "to establish an international cultural pact",
      "to eliminate poverty as a breeding ground for communism",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "The linguistic and historical theses of the 1930s were NOT about:",
    correctAnswer:
      "emphasizing Ottoman history as the most important part of Turkish history",
    propositions: [
      "creating a new national identity apart from the Ottoman past",
      "establishing links between modern Turkey and ancient Anatolian civilizations such as the Hittites",
      "boosting national pride by portraying Turkish culture as one of the oldest in the world",
      "emphasizing Ottoman history as the most important part of Turkish history",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "Who was the leader of Turkey during the 1974 Cyprus invasion?",
    correctAnswer: "Bülent Ecevit",
    propositions: [
      "Kenan Evren",
      "Bülent Ecevit",
      "Süleyman Demirel",
      "Turgut Özal",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "What was the main economic policy pursued by the Democrat Party in Turkey during the 1950s?",
    correctAnswer: "Free-market capitalism",
    propositions: [
      "Protectionism",
      "Free-market capitalism",
      "State socialism",
      "Import substitution",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following does confirm that the Democratic Party implemented liberalization policies in Turkey in the 1950s?",
    correctAnswer: "the introduction of a law to encourage foreign investment",
    propositions: [
      "the technological improvements in agriculture",
      "the implementation of five-year development plan",
      "the establishment of state banks",
      "the introduction of a law to encourage foreign investment",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "In which year did Mustafa Kemal officially announce for the first time that the Turkish script would replace the Ottoman alphabet?",
    correctAnswer: "1928",
    propositions: ["1930", "1928", "1915", "1925"],
  },
  {
    question:
      "What was the primary goal of the land reforms introduced in Turkey during the 1950s and 1960s?",
    correctAnswer: "Redistribution of land to peasants",
    propositions: [
      "Privatization of agricultural land",
      "Redistribution of land to peasants",
      "Nationalization of agricultural production",
      "Industrialization of rural areas",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which political party came to power in Turkey in 1950 ending decades of single-party rule?",
    correctAnswer: "Democrat Party (DP)",
    propositions: [
      "Justice and Development Party (AKP)",
      "Republican People's Party (CHP)",
      "Democrat Party (DP)",
      "Nationalist Movement Party (MHP)",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Ottoman government unilaterally abolished the _______ in September 1914.",
    correctAnswer: "Capitulations",
    propositions: ["Caliphate", "Empire", "Capitulations", "Sultanate"],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is CORRECT for the last years of the Democratic Party government?",
    correctAnswer:
      "Economic decline and authoritarian policies created discontent especially among the educated urban population",
    propositions: [
      "Individual and collective freedoms were enlarged",
      "The government showed solidarity with workers' movements",
      "Economic growth continued at increasing speed",
      "Economic decline and authoritarian policies created discontent especially among the educated urban population",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "How did the global economic crisis of 1929 influence economic policies in Turkey?",
    correctAnswer:
      "Turkey accepted a state-centric economic policy in the 1930s",
    propositions: [
      "Turkish government followed a free liberal market economy in the 1930s",
      "Turkish government accepted a socialist economic model in the 1930s",
      "Turkish government looked up to the United States as an example in the 1930s",
      "Turkey accepted a state-centric economic policy in the 1930s",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "From 1930 to 1946 Turkey had:",
    correctAnswer: "single-party regime",
    propositions: [
      "all of the above",
      "a socialist regime",
      "single-party regime",
      "multi-party democracy",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "What was the main objective of the Turkish National Movement during the War of Independence?",
    correctAnswer: "Preservation of territorial integrity and independence",
    propositions: [
      "Expansion of the caliphate",
      "Establishment of a communist state",
      "Preservation of territorial integrity and independence",
      "Restoration of the Ottoman Empire",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "What event marked the end of the Ottoman Empire and the beginning of the Republic of Turkey?",
    correctAnswer: "Treaty of Lausanne",
    propositions: [
      "Treaty of London",
      "Treaty of Sèvres",
      "Treaty of Versailles",
      "Treaty of Lausanne",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "The State Planning Office (Devlet Planlama Teşkilatı) was founded in 1960 in order to coordinate the developments in the fields of economic, social, and cultural planning.",
    correctAnswer: "True",
    propositions: ["True", "False"],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following WAS NOT true in regards to the immigration to Germany from Turkey?",
    correctAnswer:
      "Immigrants came back to Turkey right after they saved enough money.",
    propositions: [
      "Most immigrants faced with culture shock in Germany.",
      "It started in the 1960s.",
      "Immigrants came back to Turkey right after they saved enough money.",
      "First immigrants were considered as guest workers.",
    ],
  },
];
